# Hasan Jaffal

# Project Manager / Software Development Expert

Beirut, Lebanon - 00961 3 926130 - jaftalks@icloud.com - jaftalks.com

#### **PROFILE**

Long experience in the software development field with extensive experience in project management and software development life cycles. I have managed software projects in the private, public and non-profit sectors and have worked on international software projects across a range of industries in Africa and the middle east.

Project Management – PMP – Agile Scrum – Business Analysis – Requirements Management - Software, Web and Mobile Development - Software Architecture.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## ArabiaGIS, Lebanon

## Project Manager — 2012-Present [5 years]

Project manager at ArabiaGIS, my duties start from the sales phase, to the budgeting, planning, controlling and the delivery phase. My core role functions are:

- Managing medium to large scale international software projects.
- Deliver high-profile projects within expedited time frames while meeting all business deliverables.
- Prioritize, allocate, and follow up on tasks to project resources
- Prepare software concepts, pitch solutions and respond to RFPs.
- Engage with customers to analyze and collect user, business, and, system requirements.
- Prepare and Present analysis, and training documentation.
- Providing consultancy in Software Architecture and Design and Coding best practices.

# Senior Software Developer and Solution Architect — 2008-2012 [4 years]

Working as Software Architect, Developer and Project Leader, I was mainly responsible of the following tasks:

- To schedule, lead, achieve and follow up projects.
- To perform business, functional and technical analysis and writing technical documentation.
- To develop WPF, Silverlight, Web, Mobile and GIS applications.
- To design software solutions and select technologies and design patterns.

Hasan |affal - CV October 2016

## Sokin, Congo

## Software Developer — 2006–2008 [2 years]

Working as enterprise applications developer at Sokin:

- · Develop web and desktop applications using .NET
- · Perform requirements analysis and documentation
- Participate in System Designs and documentation

#### **EDUCATION**

2006 Lebanese University - BS in Computer Sciences

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

2012 Certified Project Management Professional, PMI

2011 Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Arabia, Beirut

#### CONFERENCES

2016 Attended the World Humanitarian Summit, Istanbul

2016 Attended the PMI Leadership Institute Conference, Barcelona

2015 Attended the PMI Regional Leadership Meeting, Dubai

2015 Organized the Second National Project Management Conference, Beirut

2015 Speaker at the Agile Tour, Beirut

2014 Speaker about Agile Scrum at AUB, Beirut

2013 Attended ESRI User Conference, Dubai

2012 Attended the First National Project Management Conference, Beirut

2012 Attended ESRI User Conference, Beirut

#### VOLUNTEERING

2015 Business Plan Development - Project Management Institute : Lebanon

**2014** Board Member and Director of Administration - Project Management Institute: Lebanon

2013 Founded talentmethods.org, helps NGOs building their online presence.

Hasan |affal - CV October 2016